Hello everyone and welcome back to EnglishPod.
大家好，欢迎回到EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
And my name is Katherine and we've got a special announcement to make today.
我是Katherine，今天我们有一个特别的消息要宣布。
That's right.
没错。
This is lesson number 200.
这是第200课。
Woohoo!
呜呼！
So good job EnglishPod.
干得好，EnglishPod。
We have over 200 lessons already in our library so that's like enough for like six months
我们的课程库里已经有超过200节课了，这大概够学六个月
of continuous learning I think.
的连续学习，我想。
But the lessons keep coming and they keep getting better so of course you should continue
但课程还在继续推出，而且越来越好，所以你当然应该继续
to listen to us.
听我们的节目。
We just thought we would mention that today is the special number 200.
我们只是想提一下，今天是特别的第200期。
Exactly.
正是。
And because it's a special number we're going to talk about a very laid back topic but very
因为是特别的日子，我们要聊一个非常轻松的话题，但
interesting nonetheless.
还是很有趣。
We're talking about junk food.
我们要聊的是垃圾食品。
You might argue that it's actually too laid back and is the cause of many problems in
你可能会说这话题太轻松了，而且正是美国和其他地方
America and other places in the world.
许多问题的根源。
Junk food is unhealthy food.
垃圾食品就是不健康的食物。
So let's take a listen to today's dialogue and we'll be back in a moment to talk about
那么，我们来听听今天的对话，稍后回来再讨论
what's going on.
具体内容。
I'm hungry.
我饿了。
Let's go grab a bite to eat.
我们去吃点东西吧。
Sure.
好啊。
How about we go home and prepare a couple of sandwiches?
我们回家做几个三明治怎么样？
Nah, let's get a burger and fries.
不，我们去买个汉堡和薯条吧。
What you ever do is have unhealthy fast food.
你总是吃不健康的快餐。
Pizza, fries, burgers and hot dogs.
披萨、薯条、汉堡和热狗。
You have to start eating better.
你得开始吃得更好一点。
What are you talking about?
你在说什么啊？
I have salads sometimes.
我有时候也吃沙拉。
Yeah, right.
是啊，说得对。
I'm serious.
我是认真的。
You should also cut down on your sugar intake as well.
你还应该减少糖分的摄入。
You drink carbonated drinks that are high in fructose syrup.
你喝的那些碳酸饮料果糖含量很高。
It's really not healthy.
真的很不健康。
Fine.
好吧。
I'll start drinking water and having home cooked meals that are low in fat.
我会开始喝水，吃低脂的家常菜。
Are you happy now?
你满意了吧？
It's a start but I'll be happy when I see you stick to your promise.
这是个开始，但看到你坚持承诺我才会高兴。
Alright, we're back.
好了，我们回来了。
So let's take a look at some of the great words and phrases all about junk food now
现在让我们来看看一些关于垃圾食品的好词好句，
in Language Takeaway.
在“语言小贴士”环节。
Language Takeaway.
语言小贴士。
My favorite.
我最喜欢的部分。
This stuff makes me hungry.
这些东西让我饿了。
But it's not very good for you.
但它对你身体不好。
It's not.
确实不好。
It's terrible.
太糟糕了。
Actually, his favorite food was burger and fries.
实际上，他最喜欢的食物是汉堡和薯条。
I had it for dinner last night.
我昨晚就吃了这个当晚餐。
Really?
真的吗？
You had burger and fries?
你吃了汉堡和薯条？
Yeah, maybe.
嗯，也许吧。
Well, it's not very healthy and there's a great way to describe this.
好吧，这不太健康，有一个很好的词可以形容它。
The word is unhealthy.
这个词是“不健康的”。
Alright, so yes, as you say, it's very unhealthy.
好的，所以是的，就像你说的，它非常不健康。
Well, yeah, because you get fat.
嗯，是啊，因为你会变胖。
They're very high in calories.
它们热量很高。
So it's unhealthy.
所以不健康。
So that means it's not good for you.
意思就是对你不好。
That's right.
没错。
So just a reminder, in English, when we hear the word unhealthy or unhappy, this means
所以提醒一下，在英语中，当我们听到“unhealthy”或“unhappy”时，这表示
not healthy, not happy.
不健康、不开心。
Un is a prefix that means not.
“Un”是一个前缀，表示“不”。
Okay, and talking about unhealthy food, in general, what are we talking about?
好的，说到不健康的食物，一般来说，我们在说什么？
We're talking about fast food.
我们在说快餐。
Okay, so this might require a story.
好的，这可能需要一个故事来解释。
What is the meaning behind fast food as opposed to slow food?
“快餐”相对于“慢餐”有什么含义？
Because there is no slow food, right?
因为并没有慢餐这种东西，对吧？
I think now they have it in like France or something like that.
我想现在法国之类的地方有。
They talk about slow food.
他们谈论慢餐。
But anyways, fast food is food that is prepared very quickly.
但不管怎样，快餐是准备得很快的食物。
So you go, you order, in two or three minutes, you have your entire order ready to go.
所以你去点餐，两三分钟，你点的所有东西就准备好了。
Okay, so maybe this is the food that I could get at McDonald's or Burger King where they
好的，所以这可能是我在麦当劳或汉堡王能买到的食物，他们
make it very, very quickly and I can go home or I can go to the office with my food ready.
做得非常快，我可以带回家或带到办公室，食物已经准备好了。
Exactly.
没错。
So fast food, very popular among countries, very popular nowadays among busy people who
所以快餐在很多国家很流行，现在在忙碌的人群中也很流行，他们
have no time to sit down at a restaurant or eat or sit down and have a proper lunch.
没时间坐下来在餐厅吃饭，或者坐下来好好吃顿午餐。
Fast food.
快餐。
And one of the important drinks at a fast food restaurant is a carbonated drink.
快餐店里一种重要的饮品是碳酸饮料。
So this carbonated, what does this mean?
那么“carbonated”是什么意思？
This is actually the fancy word for soda or for fizzy drink.
这其实是“苏打水”或“气泡饮料”的正式说法。
Fizzy, okay.
气泡的，好的。
So something that's carbonated has bubbles.
所以碳酸饮料就是有气泡的东西。
Yeah, it has bubbles.
对，它有气泡。
For example, a lot of Europeans drink carbonated water.
比如，很多欧洲人喝碳酸水。
That means water with bubbles in it.
就是带气泡的水。
That's right.
没错。
So actually, the bubbles are caused because the drink has a high concentration of a certain
实际上，气泡的产生是因为饮料中某种气体浓度很高，
gas such as carbon.
比如碳。
So that's why it has all these bubbles and it's fizzy like Coca-Cola for example.
所以它才会有这么多气泡，像可口可乐那样。
Right, Coca-Cola or Sprite, these are carbonated drinks.
对，可口可乐或雪碧，这些都是碳酸饮料。
Very good.
很好。
So you have carbonated water and you have carbonated soda.
所以有碳酸水和碳酸苏打。
What is the thing that makes soda different?
那苏打水有什么不同呢？
What is it that makes soda taste so good?
是什么让苏打水这么好喝？
It's sweet and the ingredient that makes it sweet is called fructose syrup.
是甜味，而让它变甜的原料叫果糖浆。
Fructose syrup is essentially sugar.
果糖浆本质上就是糖。
Yeah, and it comes from corn I believe, right?
是啊，而且我觉得它是从玉米里提取的，对吧？
That's right.
没错。
So you can also hear the name corn syrup and this is a sweet syrup that comes from corn
所以你也会听到“玉米糖浆”这个名字，这是一种来自玉米的甜味糖浆，
that makes drinks like Sprite and Coca-Cola taste so good.
它让雪碧和可口可乐这样的饮料变得那么好喝。
It's also very unhealthy for you.
但它对身体也非常不健康。
Yes, because it has a lot of calories.
是的，因为它含有大量卡路里。
So that is one of the main ingredients in soda.
所以那是苏打水的主要成分之一。
Now you know you have fructose syrup.
现在你知道果糖糖浆了吧。
Alright, so that's all we've got for Language Takeaway.
好了，这就是我们“语言要点”的全部内容。
Let's take another listen to today's dialogue.
让我们再听一遍今天的对话。
We'll be back in a second.
我们马上回来。
I'm hungry.
我饿了。
Let's go grab a bite to eat.
我们去吃点东西吧。
Sure.
好啊。
How about we go home and prepare a couple of sandwiches?
我们回家做几个三明治怎么样？
Nah, let's get a burger and fries.
不，我们去买个汉堡和薯条吧。
All you ever do is have unhealthy fast food.
你总是吃那些不健康的快餐。
Pizza, fries, burgers and hot dogs.
披萨、薯条、汉堡和热狗。
You have to start eating better.
你得开始吃得健康点了。
What are you talking about?
你在说什么呢？
I have salad sometimes.
我有时候会吃沙拉。
Yeah, right.
是啊，说得轻巧。
I'm serious.
我是认真的。
You should also cut down on your sugar intake as well.
你还应该减少糖分的摄入。
You drink carbonated drinks that are high in fructose syrup.
你喝的那些碳酸饮料果糖浆含量很高。
It's really not healthy.
那真的不健康。
Fine.
好吧。
I'll start drinking water and having home-cooked meals that are low in fat.
我会开始喝水，吃低脂的家常菜。
Are you happy now?
你现在满意了吧？
It's a start, but I'll be happy when I see you stick to your promise.
这是个开始，但看到你坚持承诺我才会高兴。
Alright, we're back.
好了，我们回来了。
So now we have a couple of great phrases that we heard along the dialogue.
现在我们在对话中听到了一些很棒的短语。
So let's take a look at those now in Fluency Builder.
那我们现在在流利度构建环节来看看这些短语。
Fluency Builder.
流利度构建。
Alright, so starting off.
好的，首先开始。
This is a very interesting phrase because we saw it in the first sentence and it says,
这是一个非常有趣的短语，因为我们在第一句话中看到它，它说，
let's go grab a bite to eat.
我们去随便吃点东西吧。
Let's grab a bite to eat.
So to grab is to hold something with your hand, okay, to do it quickly.
所以“grab”是用手抓住某物，表示快速做某事。
He grabbed my arm.
他抓住了我的胳膊。
So to grab a bite to eat, a bite is a small taste.
所以“grab a bite to eat”中的“bite”指的是一小口。
We're going to have a quick meal.
我们要快速吃一顿饭。
So after work, you want to go grab a bite to eat?
所以下班后，你想去随便吃点东西吗？
That means let's go have something to eat quickly.
意思是让我们去快速吃点东西。
Yeah, I'll be there soon.
好的，我马上就到。
Let me just grab a bite to eat.
让我先随便吃点东西。
So bite is a little bit.
所以“bite”就是一点点。
It's a small amount of food.
它指的是少量食物。
Now for our next phrase, it's very important because I've noticed that a lot of our English
现在来看下一个短语，它非常重要，因为我注意到很多英语
learners make the mistake of using this phrase.
学习者会误用这个短语。
It's how about.
就是“how about”。
How about.
“How about”。
So in today's dialogue, the phrase is, how about we go home and prepare a couple of sandwiches?
所以在今天的对话中，这个短语是：我们回家做几个三明治怎么样？
So how about is used as a suggestion is, how do you feel or what do you think of going
所以“how about”用作建议时，意思是：你觉得回家做几个三明治怎么样？
home and preparing a couple of sandwiches?
或者你对回家做几个三明治有什么看法？
So another way to say this is, why don't we go home and prepare some sandwiches?
所以另一种说法是：我们为什么不回家做些三明治呢？
Exactly.
没错。
But commonly, English learners make the mistake of using how about as a way of saying how
但通常，英语学习者会误用“how about”来表示“how was it”或“how is it”。
was it or how is it.
比如，你的周末怎么样？
So for example, how about your weekend?
例如，你的周末过得怎么样？
Wrong.
错了。
Okay.
好的。
So how was your weekend?
那你周末过得怎么样？
Exactly.
没错。
So how about is usually used when we make a suggestion.
所以“how about”通常用于提出建议。
How about we go see a movie on Saturday?
我们周六去看电影怎么样？
Or how about we go to my parents' house for Christmas this year?
或者今年圣诞节去我父母家怎么样？
Or finally, how about you get another job so that we can have more money to spend on
或者最后，你换份工作怎么样，这样我们就有更多钱花在
going out to eat?
外出吃饭上？
Very good.
很好。
So how about, these are all suggestions.
所以“how about”这些都是建议。
Why don't you get another job?
你为什么不换份工作？
Why don't we go to our parents' house for Christmas?
我们为什么不去父母家过圣诞节？
So you can't say, how about your weekend?
所以你不能说“how about your weekend？”
You say, how was your weekend?
你要说“how was your weekend？”
So there's a big difference there.
所以这里有很大的区别。
Very good.
很好。
So make sure to stay away from that typical mistake using how about.
所以一定要避免那个常见的错误，不要用“how about”那样说。
Now moving on, we were talking about fast food and how it's bad for you and she said,
现在继续，我们之前谈到快餐对健康不好，然后她说，
you know what?
你知道吗？
You should also cut down on your sugar intake.
你还应该减少糖的摄入量。
So to cut down, that's a phrasal verb.
所以“cut down”是一个短语动词。
That's right.
没错。
Cut down.
减少。
So that means to decrease.
意思是减少。
I'm trying to cut down on the amount of soda that I drink.
我正在努力减少喝汽水的量。
Or I'm trying to cut down on how much I spend on the weekends.
或者我正在努力减少周末的花费。
Okay.
好的。
So to cut down means to decrease or to lessen.
所以“cut down”意思是减少或降低。
Very good.
很好。
And for our last phrase, the whole thing that we're talking about and one of the favorite
至于我们最后一个短语，我们一直在谈论的，也是大家最喜欢的
meals for everyone, burger and fries.
餐点之一，汉堡和薯条。
Okay.
好的。
So this is one of many combinations for meals.
所以这是众多餐点组合之一。
You can have a burger and fries, which is a hamburger and French fries.
你可以点汉堡和薯条，也就是汉堡和炸薯条。
So oftentimes you'll say, hey, let's go grab a burger and fries.
所以通常你会说，嘿，我们去吃个汉堡和薯条吧。
Another combination, especially in England, is fish and chips.
另一种组合，尤其是在英国，是炸鱼薯条。
Yeah.
是的。
Fish and chips.
炸鱼薯条。
Fish would be a fried fish sandwich and chips would be French fries as well.
鱼是炸鱼三明治，薯条也是炸薯条。
That's right.
没错。
So actually in England, they call French fries, they call them chips.
所以实际上在英国，他们把炸薯条叫做“chips”。
So if you're confused by the word chips or potato chips and French fries, these are different
所以如果你对“chips”或“potato chips”和“French fries”这些词感到困惑，这些在不同地方
things in different places.
是不同的东西。
But if you're talking to an American, French fries is the way to go.
但如果你跟美国人说话，用“French fries”就对了。
Or for a while, they were called freedom fries.
或者有一段时间，它们被称为“freedom fries”。
Well, we don't need to talk about that.
嗯，我们不需要讨论那个。
We can talk about that in a later lesson.
我们可以在以后的课里讨论。
But for now, the phrase is burger and fries.
但现在，这个短语是“burger and fries”。
All right.
好了。
Let's listen to our dialogue for the very last time.
让我们最后一次听我们的对话。
I'm hungry.
我饿了。
Let's go grab a bite to eat.
我们去吃点东西吧。
Sure.
当然。
How about we go home and prepare a couple of sandwiches?
我们回家做几个三明治怎么样？
Nah, let's get a burger and fries.
不，我们去吃汉堡和薯条吧。
What you ever do is have unhealthy fast food.
你总是吃不健康的快餐。
Pizza, fries, burgers, and hot dogs.
披萨、薯条、汉堡和热狗。
You have to start eating better.
你得开始吃得更好。
What are you talking about?
你在说什么？
I have salads sometimes.
我有时候也吃沙拉。
Yeah, right.
是啊，说得对。
I'm serious.
我是认真的。
You should also cut down on your sugar intake as well.
你也应该减少糖的摄入量。
You drink carbonated drinks that are high in fructose syrup.
你喝的那些碳酸饮料富含果糖糖浆。
It's really not healthy.
真的很不健康。
Fine.
好吧。
I'll start drinking water and having home cooked meals that are low in fat.
我会开始喝水，吃低脂的家常菜。
Are you happy now?
你现在满意了吗？
It's a start, but I'll be happy when I see you stick to your promise.
这是个开始，但看到你遵守承诺我才会高兴。
We're back, Marco.
我们回来了，Marco。
You're laughing.
你在笑。
I know you like junk food.
我知道你喜欢垃圾食品。
What's your favorite junk food of all time?
你一直以来最喜欢的垃圾食品是什么？
Actually, I am a big, big fan of fried chicken.
其实，我是炸鸡的超级粉丝。
I love fried chicken.
我喜欢炸鸡。
Yummy.
好吃。
I don't know.
我不知道。
I think it's really greasy and oily and it's very, very bad, but I can't help it.
我觉得它很油腻，非常非常不健康，但我控制不住。
It's very good.
它太好吃了。
You can buy bags of it in America.
在美国你可以买整袋的。
I know.
我知道。
You can get like a pound bag of fried chicken.
你可以买到一磅装的炸鸡。
You buy it by the pound in America, right?
在美国是按磅买的，对吧？
Yep.
对。
You pay for how much it weighs.
你按重量付钱。
Wow.
哇。
That's amazing.
太棒了。
I actually really enjoy it, but places like Kentucky Fried Chicken, they're too expensive
我其实挺喜欢的，但像肯德基那样的地方，炸鸡太贵了。
for fried chicken.
对于炸鸡来说。
Yeah, you don't necessarily want to go there.
是啊，没必要非去那里。
There's other places that are a lot more maybe traditional that are pretty good.
还有其他更传统的地方，味道也不错。
How about you?
你呢？
What is your favorite junk food?
你最喜欢的垃圾食品是什么？
Chicago-style hot dog and french fries.
芝加哥风味热狗和薯条。
When you go to see a baseball game, you get a hot dog, but Chicago-style is good.
去看棒球赛时，你会吃热狗，但芝加哥风味的不错。
It's not too much stuff on it.
上面放的东西不多。
You have a poppy seed bun, so it's a bun, a piece of bread with some seeds on it and
用的是罂粟籽面包，就是那种带籽的面包，还有
a lot of mustard and ketchup and onions.
很多芥末、番茄酱和洋葱。
I really enjoy hot dogs, but the one thing that I cannot have on a hot dog is mustard
我很喜欢热狗，但唯一不能接受的是热狗上放芥末
or relish.
或酸黄瓜酱。
Oh my gosh.
哦，天哪。
Those are the two best things.
那可是最好吃的两样东西。
Okay, I can't talk to you anymore.
好吧，我不能再跟你说话了。
Well, tell us what your favorite junk food is and tell Marco that he's crazy if he doesn't
那么，告诉我们你最喜欢的垃圾食品是什么，并告诉马可，如果他不喜欢芥末，他就是疯了。
like mustard.
不喜欢芥末。
Our website is EnglishPod.com.
我们的网站是EnglishPod.com。
Ask us questions as well.
也欢迎向我们提问。
We're happy to answer them.
我们很乐意回答。
Until next time.
下次再见。
Bye, everyone.
大家再见。
Thanks for watching.
感谢观看。